各位大英姐妹早晨
Good morning brothers and sisters
我們在港澳之先再一次同心低頭祈禱
Let's pray
蔡恩主我們感謝你
Father God thank you so much
因為你是我們唯一食不敬拜的真神
Because you are the one true God that we worship
你吩咐我們
You have commanded us
你都告訴我們有異象問就滅亡
You've told us that without vision that we will perish
求天賦你的靈
現在在我們的心靈裏面
開啟我們的心靈
May the spirit of you, the Father, open the spirit in us
主啊求你的靈向向我們說話
May your spirit speak to us
祈禱奉教主耶穌基督的名靠
In Jesus' name we pray
Amen
我想有一段經文大家很熟悉的
I think there is a verse that is very familiar to all of us
就說按著命定人人都有一死
死後且有審判
It says and just as it is appointed for man to die once
and after that comes judgment
所以我們每一個人都會有一天要交帳的
So one day we are accountable to God
and we have to look at the past
而我們每一個人都要明白就是
我們在世界上所做的事
和所作的決定
無論是善惡都會被神去檢視
So one day there will be judgment
God will judge all that we do
whether it is good or it is evil
所以死後且有審判
意思就是說我們會有後果的
When there comes judgment after death
it means that there are consequences
所以對我們每個記憶圖來說
我們知道這個福音的必需性
So to us Christians
we have to know the necessity of the gospel
因為唯有我們得著基督
在受審判的時候
我們才可以無罪釋放
Because as we know
only when we know Christ as our Lord
that when we get judged that will be saved
另外一段經文大家很熟悉的就是說
趁著白日
我們必須做猜我來的那位的工
黑夜來到就沒有人能做工了
Another familiar verse says we must work
the works of Him who sent me while it is day
night is coming when no one can work
白日
daylight
可能是說我們還有在世在生的日子
Maybe it means that we are still living on earth
也代表著神的恩典還存在
讓我們可以去回應祂
Maybe it means that God's grace is still here
that we can respond to Him
當黑夜來到
But when night comes
我們的生命沒有了
When we die
完結了
When we end
我們神的恩典
我們不在神的恩典的時代裡面的時候
Maybe we are not in the era of God's grace
黑夜來到沒有人能做工了
The night is here and no one can work
所以有一個時效性的
So there is a limit of time
所以這段經文也提醒我和你把握時機
就因為福音是有一個迫切性的
This verse also tells us that we have to seize the divine moment
because there is an urgency of the gospel
但我和你相信了一段時間的話
So you and I have become Christians for some time
有時候我們日復一日這樣生活
Maybe day after day we live just as usual
我們會看到有機會來
有機會過去
We see opportunities come and opportunities go
我們錯過這次的機會
我們下次再等下下次機會
Maybe we miss this opportunity
and we say oh yeah the next time will come
但是聖經告訴我們那個迫切性
But the Bible tells us there is an urgency
是一個神聖的時刻
And it is a divine moment
是有一個機會這段時間裡面你需要去做的
And there is an opportunity that we have to seize
that we have to do it like now
雖然星期五世衛組織正式宣佈
但是新冠狀病毒的緊急令已經結束了
So who said that the emergency of COVID is actually now lifted
但是我們過去三年從新冠狀病毒學到什麼
But what have we learned from COVID the past three years
我們學到生命的短暫
We've learned that life is short
生命的無常
生命的失控
也有很多變幻莫測的狀況
人生命的短暫
這些功課會不會現在結束就好像忘記了
這些很重要的生命的功課
這些我們過去三年學到的教訓
我們在新冠狀病毒結束的時候都會忘記
又或者大家有沒有看到
很多的研究報告都說
如果基督徒不再努力傳福音的話
根據一些調查報告
在二零七零年
如果基督徒不再努力傳福音的話
根據一些調查報告
如果聖靈和你說話 你可以舉手
第二個邀請
你願意接受主的差遣
你說我今天聽了主的話
我願意接受主的差遣
求主打開我屬靈的眼睛
知道怎樣去回應祂
如果這個是你
請你舉手示意一下
你願意接受主的差遣
求主差遣
打開你的眼睛知道怎樣回應祂
第三個邀請
你願意行常的禱告
求主不單止差遣你自己
更加差遣你身邊的弟兄姊妹
與神同工
如果這個是你
請你舉手示意一下
感謝主
我們同心低頭祈禱
蔡恩主我們感謝你
因為你的話語是寶貴的
求你幫助我們
有一份從你而來的憐憫的心腸
以致我們的屬靈眼睛被開啟
我們願意被主的差遣
我們願意與主的同工
我們祈禱這些事情
在耶穌的名義中
阿彌陀佛